<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on My Portfolio</title><link>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on My Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Lobster PCB Mill</title><link>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/the-lobster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/the-lobster/</guid><description>Project in Action About the Project (Description Needed)
Project Website Project Github</description></item><item><title>Autonomous All Terrain Rover</title><link>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/rover/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/rover/</guid><description>Project in Action About the Project As an assignment in preperation for 4th year design projects, I created an all-terain autonomous rover with 4 of my friends over the course of a month. The rover is designed to accurately and autonomously navigate an obstacle course containing sandy and rocky terrain, as well as pit traps. The rover is equipped to assess it&amp;rsquo;s position and orientation within the course, and make adjustments accordingly.</description></item><item><title>Ludum Dare 48 - "Down Dog"</title><link>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/down-dog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/down-dog/</guid><description>Project in Action About the Project For the Ludum Dare 48 game jam, I created a pixel art platformer with one of my oldest friends. In this game you descend through a dungeon level with 2 different enemy types, special obstacles, and fight a boss at the end. Since the game is fairly short, a timer is included for those who decide to speedrun the game.
This game was created in the Godot Engine, with all art, sound, and programming being completed within the span of the game jam.</description></item><item><title>Handheld Console Emulator</title><link>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/emulator-v1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/emulator-v1/</guid><description>Project in Action About the Project As an introduction to Schematic Capture, PCB Design, and Circuit Design, I decided to build a custom handheld emulator based around the Raspberry PI. For this project, I wanted to create a handheld emulator capable of emulating consoles from the PS1 era and before. I wanted to include analog joysticks for input, a reusable battery and charging circuit, as well as a touch screen for use with Nintendo DS emulation.</description></item><item><title>Autonomous Chess Playing robot</title><link>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/chess-robot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/chess-robot/</guid><description>Project in Action About the Project As a first year project, I created a chess playing robot with two of my friends over the course of a month. The robot can accurately navigate the board, pick up pieces, and perform any legal chess move (including castling and en-passant). The robot can asses the current state of the board, make an informed decision, and execute a chosen move autonomously.
The robot was designed using the LEGO NXT robotics kit, and used custom laser cut gears and tracks in the assembly.</description></item><item><title>Ludum Dare 40 - "Make It Home"</title><link>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/make-it-home/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/make-it-home/</guid><description>Project in Action About the Project For the ludum dare 40 game jam, I created a low-poly 3D driving game my best friend from high school. In the game you must dodge the obstacles scattered about the road, but the twist is that the game will apply several disorienting effects to make the driving experience more difficult.
This game was created in the Unity Engine using C#, with all art, sound, and programming being completed within the span of the 72 hour game jam.</description></item><item><title>Snowboard Madness</title><link>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/snowboard-madness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/snowboard-madness/</guid><description>Project in Action About the Project Snowboard madness is a pseudo-3D game created in Java as a project for a programming summer camp I attended. This project uses simple linear equations to give the illusion of sprites approaching in 3D space. This project was completed in 12 total hours over the course of two days.
Project on Github</description></item><item><title>Terrarithmetic</title><link>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/terrarithmetic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.ddwhite.space/projects/terrarithmetic/</guid><description>Project in Action About the Project Terrarithmetic is an math teaching game I created with a friend in grade 10 as a cumulative project. This project was written entirely in Java without the use of any 3rd party libraries whatsoever.
The project is heavily inspired by old top-down pokemon games, and uses a math based combat system to teach basic arithmetic operations such as addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division.
For this project, I had to implement a custom tile based world, and tile based rendering engine, as well as custom asset management, input handlers, and audio handlers.</description></item></channel></rss>